# Saksham Agrawal

■ sakshama135@gmail.com 
 8850783353 in saksham-agrawal-052ab8106

#### Profile

**Experienced Finance Student** with a demonstrated history of working in the investment management industry along with an experience in team management. Skilled in Data Analysis, Quantitative Analytics, Electronics, Machine Learning, and Trading. Strong research professional currently pursuing a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science + M.Sc focused in Economics from Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani.

## **Professional Experience**

Samhita Social Ventures

May 2019 - Jul 2019 Mumbai, India

Development Intern

Work was focused on Business Development and acquiring clients. Major aspect of the work included researching different Social Sectors along with the task of providing a "snapshot" report of all firms investing in the sector. Was able to complete a full analysis of Water Conservation sector including a 5 year timeline for the firm with product recommendations and strategies.

2018 - Aug 2019

DRDO, INMAS Lab, Delhi

Proiect Lead

Lead a project under DRDO, Delhi, to develop a reconnaissance system by using ROS and computer vision. Responsibilities included team management, and maintaining the project timeline. Main coding language for the software was Python. Phase 1 of the project was completed successfully.

2018 - Oct 2019

Worldquant LLC. Research Consultant

Worked as a alpha researcher. Developed trading strategies for global markets and developed framework to backtest the same on time series data

### Research

## Volatility transmission between international markets: Analysis using MGARCH-BEKK model

2020

With increasing globalization, the links between markets have started to become stronger. As a result, markets now hold significant influence on other international markets. The study measures this effect by measuring the volatility transmitted from a market to another. The model used for analysis is the Multivariate GARCH model (BEKK(1,1))

First draft complete. Under review by a journal

#### Stock market volatility prediction using VAR-ML hybrid model

2020

The aim of this study is to study the next-day prediction accuracy of RNNs, when the input data is the market volatility, as compared to when VAR residual data is used additionally with market volatility.

First draft completed. Under review by a journal

## Fixed Income Attribution: Analysis of fixed-income portfolios

2020

Increasing the explainability of fixed income portfolio returns using fixed income attribution. The study analyzes returns of three Indian fixed income portfolios to explain their returns and study changes over the first guarter of 2020 First draft completed. Under review by supervising professor

### Community analysis of International stock markets

2020

Study focused on exploring community dynamics over the period of 2008-2020. The countries, whose stock markets are analyzed are, India, Japan, China, Singapore, Hong Kong, US & UK. Networks are significantly important for policy makers and investors too, since it enables an analysis of the group behavior of the markets, which is a major aim of the study

First draft completed. Under review by supervising professor

2019

The study tests the effectiveness of bond yields in predicting recessions in multiple countries, by using a modification of the Markov regime-switching model, which uses external regressors to calculate a time-varying transition probability developed by Andrew J. Filardo in 1998

First draft completed. Under review by supervising professor

## **Projects**

**Project PINAKA** 2017 - Sep 2019

Research project inspired from ETH Zurich. The main aim was to automate flight systems to make high endurance flights using **Artificial Intelligence**. Project received significant funds in 2018-19 and was brought to prototype stage successfully. Major responsibility was team management and securing funds

**Reconnaissance using Networked Robots** 

The project was done in collaboration with DRDO with the main aim to develop a network of drones for border surveillance.

Oct 2018 - Aug 2019

#### **Awards**

**Boeing BUILD National Award** 

Boeing India Pvt. Ltd.

Secured first place in Boeing BUILD for presenting Project PINAKA as a viable product/business model to a jury of Venture Capitalists, after clearing 5 stages of the competition from April to August 2019

Gave a 3 minute elevator pitch in the final round against 36 other teams at Boeing India Headquarters. The presentation included a complete research of the target sector, competitors and a 5 year market plan for the proposed product

**CEERI National Innovation Award** 

CSIR. CEERI Pilani

Received second position for giving a team presentation on "Project PINAKA" under the green technologies category. Jury composed of several distinguished scientists from CEERI Pilani.

Jan 17, 2019

Aug 2019

	S	kills	
Python R		ROS Robot Operating Software	
Java		LaTex	
Java		MySQL	

#### Interests

#### **Artificial Intelligence**

Worked on several open-source projects related to AI. Wish to pursue a career developing my skills in AI, specifically to develop an AI agent which has real life application.

#### Leadership/ Management

Wish to work in firms that give me a direct exposure to clients or let me handle teams. Have a strong sense of leadership having managed several technical teams, the past 3 years in college

#### **Education**

Birla Institute Of Technology and Science, Pilani

B.Tech Computer Science + M.Sc. Economics

**CGPA: 7.5** 

**IITians PACE** Class 12th Maharashtra Board: 87%

**Atomic Energy Central School** 

Class 10th CBSE Board: 95%

2017 - present Goa, India

2015 - 2016

Mumbai, India

2005 - 2014

Mumbai, India

Courses/ MOOCs			
The Data Scientist's Toolbox  Johns Hopkins University   Coursera  https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/JNDDRYTZD5U  C	Oct 2018 - Dec 2018		
Applied Plotting, Charting & Data Representation in Python University of Michigan   Coursera https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/F7LG78YCP8WG	Aug 2018 - Oct 2018		
Machine Learning Stanford University    Coursera https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/85LHHW7TAKY D	Jun 2018 – Sep 2018		

Introduction to Data Science in Python

University of Michigan || Coursera

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/ZFDFK9DY9Y9X

Jun 2018 – Jul 2018